Guide to the Poly Archives Video Collection RG.003
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Poly Archives Video Collection
1975-2007
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
RG.003
12 Cubic Feet 12 boxes
Scope and Contents
This collection of VHS and U-matic tapes spans from 1975 to 2007. The tapes cover aspects of university life, events, and faculty. While this finding aid refers to the physical magnetic tapes, digital surrogates of some tapes are available to view in the archives. Further distribution of such tapes is dependent on copyright restrictions.
Biographical / Historical
The Poly Archives Video Collection is comprised of VHS and U-matic tapes deposited to the Poly Archives by the University. The University changed names two times between 1973 and 2007, thus there are two creators cited: Polytechnic Institute of New York and Polytechnic University. Some tapes in this collection were produced by corporations outside of the University, but contain content featuring the University, such as television spots and interviews.
In 2013, these tapes were digitized by New York University's Digital Library Technology Services department in order to preserve the content. This finding aid refers to the original magnetic tapes, which are housed in the archives.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
Tapes are arranged by subject, then chronologically, into seven series:
Series I: Promotional Series II: Lectures and Interviews Series III: Television Spots Series IV: Events Series V: Scholarships Series VI: Meetings Series VII: Alumni and Former Faculty
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
Audio-visual materials
- Series I: Promotional, 1989-2005
  - Subseries A: General, 1989-2005
    - Reflections of 10 Years: Up Close and Personal, 2005; VHS tape (Box 1)
    - Polytechnic University Leadership for the 21st Century, 1998; VHS tape (Box 1)
    - The Campaign for Polytechnic University, 1997; VHS tape (Box 1)
    - Polytechnic Institute Graphic Opening and Closing, 1996; U-matic tape (Box 1)
    - Polytechnic Institute Graphics Test, 1996; U-matic tape (Box 1)
    - Polytech first tape 1995 May 24, VHS tape (Box 1)
    - Polytechnic Video 1994, 1995, U-matic tape (Box 1)
    - Polytech Video 1993, U-matic tape (Box 1)
    - Pride is Building, 1991; VHS tape (Box 1)
    - "Polytechnic" In Progress, 1990; VHS tape (Box 1)
    - Polytechnic University 1989, VHS tape (Box 1)
    - Polytechnic University "Challenging the Future", undated; U-matic tape (Box 1)
    - A New University for a New Century, undated; U-matic tape (Box 1)
    - Polytech Logos, undated; U-matic tape (Box 1)
    - Polytech Logos Tape #8, undated; VHS tape (Box 1)
  - Subseries B: Departments and Centers, 1992-2000
    - Raising the Bar on Hi-Tech Incubators (1 of 3), 2000; VHS tape (Box 2)
    - Polytechnic University Media Training, 1995; U-matic tape (Box 2)
    - Center for Biotechnology (revised), 1992; VHS tape (Box 2)
  - Subseries C: MetroTech, 1990-1995
    - Polytech 1995 June 5, VHS tape (Box 2)
    - MetroTech, 1990; U-matic tape (Box 2)
    - Cut aways: Campus (tape #11), undated; VHS tape (Box 2)
    - MetroTech/Dr. D. Chang (tape #4), undated; VHS tape (Box 2)
  - Subseries D: Students
    - Interactive Subway Kiosk, 1992; VHS tape (Box 2)
    - Campus filming: Student interviews (tape #5), undated; VHS tape (Box 2)
    - Student Interviews/Campus (tape #7), VHS tape (Box 2)
    - Campus/Students (tape #9), undated; VHS tape (Box 2)
    - Lab shots/students (tape #10), undated; VHS tape (Box 2)
    - Student Quotes (Tape #12), undated; VHS tape (Box 2)
    - Student interviews about Polytechnic, undated; VHS tape (Box 2)
  - Subseries E: Miscellaneous, 1995
    - Polytech Shoot: Second Tape, 1995; VHS tape (Box 3)
    - Polytech Shoot tape 4, 1995; U-matic tape (Box 3)
    - Polytech Shoot tape 5, 1995; U-matic tape (Box 3)
    - Polytech Shoot tape 6, 1995; U-matic tape (Box 3)
    - Polytech Shoot tape 7, 1995; U-matic tape (Box 3)
    - Polytech Shoot tape 8, 1995; U-matic tape (Box 3)
    - Polytech Shoot tape 9, 1995; U-matic tape (Box 3)
    - Cut-Aways Polytech Univer., 1995; U-matic tape (Box 3)
    - Cut-aways Polytech, undated; VHS tape (Box 3)
    - Wassef Sisters (tape #2), undated; VHS tape (Box 3)
    - Polytechnic University Roughcut with select quotes, undated; U-matic tape (Box 3)
    - Polytechnic Auditions, undated; U-matic tape (Box 3)
    - Notes to Tape RG-3_ref37 (Polytech Shoot Tape 4), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Notes to Tape RG-3_ref38 (Polytech Shoot Tape 5), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Notes to Tape RG-3_ref39 (Polytech Shoot Tape 6), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Notes to Tape RG-3_ref40 (Polytech Shoot Tape 7), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Notes to Tape RG-3_ref42 (Polytech Shoot Tape 9), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series II: Lectures and Interviews, 1989-2004
  - Subseries A: Faculty and Administration Interviews, 1989-2004
    - Dr. Eli Pearce interviewed by Christopher Hayes, 2004; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - "Biology, Machines, and Society" George Bugliarello, 1999; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Joel Tobias Interview, 1996; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Interview with President Bugliarello, 1994; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Stuart Dim, 1990; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Bugliarello/Hart/Nagabhushan, 1989; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Professor Donald Hunt, undated; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Scott Carpenter and Roy Freedman, undated; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - George Bugliarello Interview: "Knight Lines: The Future of Man and Machine", undated; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Frank Leiber Lecture, undated; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - David Chang Interview, undated; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Shustek, Leonard (tape #3), undated; VHS tape (Box 4)
  - Subseries B: Leadership Seminar Series, 1995-1996
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Dr. Willaim C.W. Mow "A System Engineer's Success in Merchandising ", 1996 November 4; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Craig G. Matthews "Your Career: Choices Not Made", 1996 October 28; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Dr. Gerhard Frohlich "Engineering and Engineering Management", 1996 October 21; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: James A. Dobkin "Engineering and the Practice of Law", 1996 September 30; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Jerome H. Lemelson "A Conversation with Jerome H. Lemelson Entrepreneur and Inventor Extraordinaire", 1996 April 8; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Jack M. Sipress "Advances in International Communications Via Undersea Systems", 1996 March 18; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Dr. Shelley A. Harrison "Building New High-Tech Companies", 1996 March 11; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Anthony M. Johnson "The Career of a Physicist in Industry and the University (Lasers and Ultrafast Optical Phenomena)", 1996 March 4; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: John G. Puente "International Satellite Communications", 1996 February 26; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Leonard Berkowitz "A Lifetime of Learning at Exxon", 1996 February 19; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Eleanor K. Baum "Changing the Face of Engineering", 1996 February 5; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Mel Horwitch "Business Management for the Twenty-first Century", 1996 January 29; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Robert D. Dalziel "International Telecommunications", 1995 November 27; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Frank Pavadan "An Engineer's Career in State Government", 1995 November 13; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: John S. Mayo "The Future of Telecommunications", 1995 November 6; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Irene Van Slyke "How to Win Elections", 1995 October 30; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: Eugene Fasullo "The Role of Engineers in Rebuilding Our Country", 1995 October 9; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Leadership Seminar Series: David A. Conkiln "Career Opportunities in Manufacturing", 1995 October 2; VHS tape (Box 4)
  - Subseries C: Lynford Lectures, 1998-2004
    - Lynford Lecture 2004, VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Lynford Lecture: Bill Joy, 2000; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Lynford Lecture: Dr. J. Craig Ventor, 1999; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Inaugural Lynford Lecture, 1998; VHS tape (Box 4)
  - Subseries D: Teaching videos, 1992-1998
    - Money, 1992; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Culture War, 1992; VHS tape (Box 4)
    - Haldun Written Lecture '98, 1998
- Series III: Television Spots, 1975-2006
  - Subseries A: News Coverage, 1982-2006
    - Jerry Hultin (Polytechnic University) on News 55 Focus, 2006; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Jerry Hultin on Port Security, 2006; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Interview with Jerry Hultin on Lou Dobbs Tonight, 2006; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Polytechnic U. to Honor Astronaut Charles Camarda, 2005; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Polytechnic University -- Prof. Nasir Memon -- Homeland Security, 2005; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Interview with Vickram Kapila -- HS Teachers and Robotics, 2003; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Story about Abdellah Higazi, 2002; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Abdellah Higazi -- Polytechnic Student, 2002; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Stabbing at Polytechnic University (WNJU), 2002; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Stabbing at Polytechnic University (multiple news stations), 2002; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Interview with Dr. Kalle Levon -- Bioterrorism, 2001; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Interview with Bud Griffis, 2001; VHS tapes (Box 5)
    - Brooklyn Colleges -- NY-1 News All Morning, 2001; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - NY-1 News: Joe Jacobs, 1999; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Science Fair UPN News at 10pm, 1999; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Professor Robert Ratay, 1999; VHS tapes (Box 5)
    - Future City Competition, 1999; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - TV/Radio Coverage: Othmer Gift, 1998; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - John Falcocchio -- Shrinking Parking Lots, 1998; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Polytechnic University on CNN's News Stand, 1998; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Donation to Polytechnic University, 1998; VHS tape (Box 9)
    - Update of Polytechnic University, 1997; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Student Center, 1996; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Professor Sforza/Polytechnic Univ., 1996; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Polytechnic (The Ten O'Clock News), 1996; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Malaysian Student, 1996; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Students Build a Canoe, 1994; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Polytechnic University Scholarshop Program, 1994; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Building a Race Car and Formula 1 Racing Car, 1993; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Ron Brown Visits MetroTech, 1993; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Polytechnic University Dedicates New Facility, 1992; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Dr. Pasquale Sforza: LaGaurdia Airport, 1992; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Polytechnic University Scholarships and Prof. Latourette, 1992; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Robert Maxwell Donates $10M to Polytechnic University, 1991; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - "The Promise Fund/Polytechnic University" Positively Black, 1991; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Polytech University Ground Breaking, 1990; VHS tape (Box 5)
    - Peter Davis: Polytechnic University on "Live at Five", 1990; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - Live at Five Open, 1990; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - Bridge Collapse, 1987; VHS tape (Box 6)
    - Bridge Collapse, 1987; VHS tape
    - Shuttle Failure, 1986; U-matic tape
    - MetroTech -- Project of Polytechnic University on Eyewitness News, 1986; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - Polytechnic Institute of N. Y. Mexican Earthquake, 1985; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - MetroTech Editorial, 1985; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - Chemistry Magic-Polytechnic Institute, 1985; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - Polytechnic in Brooklyn, 1985; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - Metro Tech-Brooklyn Development, 1984; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - Fire at Polytechnic Graduation (WOR, WPIX, WNEW), Probably 1983; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - Fire at Polytechnic Graduation (CNN), Probably 1983; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - Fire at Polytechnic Graduation (WCBS, WNBC, WABC), Probably 1983; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - Segment on College Graduates, 1982; U-matic tape (Box 6)
    - David Mermelstein -- Polytechnic University, 1982; U-Matic tape (Box 7)
    - Commencement Exercises -- Queens College and Polytech Institute, 1982; U-matic tape (Box 7)
    - Today Show Excerpts, 1975; U-matic tape (Box 7)
    - Job Search- Gerald Sandler's Interview on Channel 12, undated; VHS tape (Box 7)
    - Luncheon at Polytech, undated; U-matic tape (Box 7)
    - Interview with George Bugliarello on the Dick Roffman & Helen Haddad Discover New York Show, undated; U-matic tape (Box 7)
    - Computer Fraud, undated; U-matic tape (Box 7)
    - Dr. Alan Molaf, undated; U-matic tape (Box 7)
    - Bridge Inspection, undated; U-matic tape (Box 7)
    - Promise Fund coverage on WNBC News, undated; VHS tape (Box 7)
  - Subseries B: The Scientific Minute
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #1: Sailing by Computer, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #2: Drug Abuse, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #4: Computer Chess, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #7: Hypnosis, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #10: Saturn, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #11: Rail Gun, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #12: Heart Surgery, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #14: Mummies, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #15: Apes, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #16: Antartica, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #17: Training Engineers, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #18: Telescopes, 1980; U-matic tape (Box 8)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #19: Radioactive Waste, 1981; U-matic tape (Box 9)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #20: Cold Weather on Mount Washington, 1981; U-matic tape (Box 9)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #21: Bioluminescence, 1981; U-matic tape (Box 9)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #22: Space Shuttle, 1981; U-matic tape (Box 9)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #23: The Coyote, 1981; U-matic tape (Box 9)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #26: Dieting, 1981; U-matic tape (Box 9)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #27: Artificial Hearts, 1981; U-matic tapes (Box 9)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #28: Self Protection for Plants, 1981; U-matic tape (Box 9)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #29: The Human Memory, 1981; U-matic tape (Box 9)
    - "The Scientific Minute" Program #30: DNA, 1981; U-matic tape (Box 9)
  - Subseries C: Miscellaneous
    - Brooklyn Community Access Television Bulletin Board Promo, 1993; VHS tape (Box 9)
    - Improving Math Skills in Education, 1989; VHS tape (Box 9)
    - MetroTech: Off the set, 1985; U-matic tape (Box 9)
    - The New Long Island Partnership Education Campaign PSA, undated; VHS tape (Box 9)
- Series IV: Events, 1989-2003
  - Subseries A: Commencement and Honorary degrees
    - Tadahiro Sekimoto Honorary Degree, 1998; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Polytechnic University 1995 Commencement Part I, VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Polytechnic University 1995 Commencement Part II, VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Polytech Shoot tape 10 (home video of graduation), 1995; U-matic tape (Box 10)
    - Commencement 1989, VHS tape (Box 10)
  - Subseries B: Groundbreaking and Dedications
    - Jacobs Academic Bldg Dedication, 2002; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Othmer Resident Hall Dedication, 2002; VHS tapes (Box 10)
    - Polytechnic University Groundbreaking Ceremony Joseph J. and Violet J. Jacobs Building, 2000; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Polytechnic Dedication, 1992; VHS tape (Box 10)
  - Subseries C: Receptions and Symposia
    - 70th Birthday Party for Professor Eli Pearce, 1999; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Polytechnic University ME 100 Symposium Part 1, 1999; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Ace Fall Reception, 1997; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Perl Reception, 1996; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Tribute Dinner, 1994; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Ishmael Robleh, Outstanding Student of the Year, Award Dinner, 1995; U-matic tape (Box 10)
    - Distinguished Service Award for Science and Technology Dinner, 1990; VHS tape (Box 10)
  - Subseries D: Student events, 1989-2003
    - WISA International Dance Event, 2003; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Tour de Sol, 1996; U-matic tape (Box 10)
    - Poly Electric Car Tour de Sol Race, 1996; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - ASCE Concrete Canoe Competition, 1996; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Career Fair, 1995; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Taiwan Trip, 1994; VHS tape (Box 10)
    - Science Camp, 1989; U-matic tape (Box 10)
    - Dubbed from VHS C: labelled "volleyball", undated; VHS tape (Box 10)
- Series V: Scholarships, 1990-2003
  - Subseries A: Promise Fund, 1990-2003
    - Broad Street Polytechnic University: The Promise Fund, 2003; VHS tape (Box 11)
    - Promise Scholars Induction Ceremony, 2002; VHS tape (Box 11)
    - Promise Fund Video 2001, VHS tape (Box 11)
    - Polytechnic University Promise Fund 2000, VHS tape (Box 11)
    - Polytechnic University Promise Fund 1999, VHS tape (Box 11)
    - The Promise Fund: A Decade of Progress, 1998; VHS tape (Box 11)
    - 1997 Promise Fund, VHS tape (Box 11)
    - Promise Fund, 1996; VHS tape (Box 11)
    - 1995 Promise Fund Dinner, VHS tape (Box 11)
    - 1994 Promise Fund, U-matic tape (Box 11)
    - 1994 Promise Fund, VHS tape (Box 11)
    - Promise Fund Dinner 1993, U-matic tape (Box 11)
    - Promise Fund Dinner [Original], 1993; VHS tape (Box 11)
    - The Promise Fund: "Making a Difference" Parts 1 & 2, 1990; VHS tape (Box 11)
    - Making a Difference: Part 2, 1990; U-matic tape (Box 11)
    - Promise Fund PSAs, 1990; VHS tape (Box 11)
  - Subseries B: P.R.I.D.E., 1995
    - Multimedia Review #1 from P.R.I.D.E, 1995; VHS tape (Box 11)
  - Subseries C: Lemelson Scholars, 2000
    - Lemelson Scholars Induction Ceremony, 2000; VHS tape (Box 11)
- Series VI: Meetings, 1994-2007
  - Subseries A: Meetings of the Retired Faculty, 1998-2000
    - Louis Menashe- Reflections on Post-Soviet Russia (almost) Ten Years Later, 2000; VHS tape (Box 12)
    - Lunch meeting, 1999; VHS tape (Box 12)
    - Stan Preiser- An Historical Survey of TIAA-CREF Performance, 1999; VHS tape (Box 12)
    - Aaron Kershenbaum, 1999; VHS tape (Box 12)
    - Don Scarl- Undergrad Education in Physics, Math, and Engineering, 1999; VHS tape (Box 12)
    - Deane Yang- Undergrad Education in Math, 1998; VHS tape (Box 12)
    - Installation- Lunch Meeting, 1998; VHS tape (Box 12)
    - Nominations and Elections, Kilcommons- "Oxford Medical Update", 1998; VHS tape (Box 12)
  - Subseries B: Town Hall Meeting, 1994-2007
    - Polytechnic Town Hall Meeting, 2007; VHS tape (Box 12)
    - Town Meeting with Dr. Chang, 1994; VHS tape (Box 12)
  - Subseries C: Miscellaneous, 2007
    - John Saxton Meeting, 2007; VHS tape (Box 12)
- Series VII: Alumni and Former Faculty, 1985-1997
  - Subseries A: Biographical Information, 1985-1997
    - Jacobs Foundation featured on Adam Smith's "Giving Away Millions", 1997; VHS tape (Box 12)
    - William Butcher Photo, 1990; U-matic tape (Box 12)
    - Carl Morse Photo, 1990; U-matic tape (Box 12)
    - Burndy Library: As My Fathers Planted Before Me, 1985; VHs tape (Box 12)
    - Soros Tape, Undated; VHS tape (Box 12)
    - George Bugliarello: A Tribute, Undated; VHS tape (Box 12)
  - Subseries B: Events, 1995
    - Polytechnic University 1995 -- 25th Class Reunion, VHS tape (Box 12)
    - Alumni Leadership Series: Entrepreneurship in ?, Undated; VHS tape (Box 12)
  - Subseries C: Interviews, 1995 (Box 12)
    - Leonard Shustek Interview (Polytech alum), 1995; U-matic tape (Box 12)
  - Subseries D: Miscellaneous
    - Flat Art Shots for Shelley Lewis R-1, 1997; U-Matic tape (Box 12)
    - Flat Art Shots for Shelley Lewis R-2, 1997; U-matic tape (Box 12)